淘宝搜索店铺：我爱美剧创意周边
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  赛太公中路狂草  赛太公下路狂虐
翻译:  洗七里    Eunice油腻希
校对:  五路皆神赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第二十一集
爸  来陪我练投球好吗
Daddy, want to come throw with me?
其实我现在有点忙...
Oh, actually -- I'm actually in the middle of --
-没问你  -好吧
- Not you. - Okay.
好  但只能在歌洛莉亚和乔
Oh, uh, yeah, but just for a bit while, uh, Gloria and Joe
去车库挑你的旧玩具这段时间练一会儿
go through some of your old toys in the garage.
我飞过去
I'll fly there.
好  快点
Okay, vamanos!
这孩子特别喜欢那披风
Kid loves that cape.
看来你不那么介意儿子穿其他服装配饰了
So, I see your stance on sons wearing accessories has evolved.
那件披风赋予他超能力
The cape gives him superpowers.
你当年穿的暖腿袜赋予你什么了
What did leg warmers give you?
时髦值  它们让我时髦值大增
Flair. They gave me flair.
别烦我了好吗
Leave me alone, okay?
所有人都别烦我
Everybody, leave me alone.
你这是怎么了
Hey! What's all that?
抱歉  我只是需要独自放松一晚
I just -- I'm sorry. I just need a night away.
来  帮我一把好吗
Here. Want to help?
-我不干这种活  -好吧
- I don't do that. - Okay.
最近压力有点爆棚了
It's just -- It's been a lot recently,
一起审理了特别久的官司终于结束了
you know, coming off of a really long trial,
小卡疯了一样做春季大扫除
Cam's spring cleaning frenzy,
为莉莉大采购垒球用品
hauling Lily all over for softball,
还要假装对垒球感兴趣
pretending to care about softball.
我懂想要独自放松一下的感觉
Oh, I get needing time away.
和你妈结婚那些年让我深有体会
I was married to your mother.
就像你现在这样
Like you are now.
我全都计划好了
I have it all planned out.
我开车到沙漠那边去
I drive to the desert.
入住万锦酒店
I check into the Markham --
在泳池边休息几小时  做个按摩
a few hours by the pool, massage,
然后下楼去吃多汁的牛排与薯条
then I head downstairs for a juicy steak frites,
随身只带一本书  书不会开口烦我
just me and my book, which can't talk to me.
那就去
So do it.
问小卡我能不能自己出门
Asking Cam to go away alone
会让他感情受伤发疯三周
is three weeks of wounded crazy
我现在真的没有心力去面对他那样
that I -- I don't want to deal with right now.
别问  直接说
Don't ask, tell.
不问  不说是美军早年对军中同性恋者的政策
这不是你们基佬一直在争取的权益吗
Isn't that what you fought for?
你这话让我不知道该从哪里开始纠正
Okay, I don't know what to address first.
杰  歌洛莉亚准备好回家了
Uh, Jay, Gloria's ready to go.
好  你别太紧张
All right. Take it easy.
也祝你今天愉快  塔克太太
You have a good one, too... Mrs. Tucker.
他为什么叫你塔克太太
Why'd he call you Mrs. Tucker?
他又为什么穿那么没线条的牛仔裤  谁知道
Why does he wear those boxy jeans? I don't know.
不  说真的  他为什么又在吐槽你
No, seriously. W-Why is he messing with you?
好吧  说就说
All right, yeah, what the hell.
我告诉他我很想
Um, I told him how I would love to go
去沙漠里放松一晚
to the desert for a night.
好啊  多有趣  我们去吧
Okay, yeah. Fun. Let's go!
请等一下
Hold, please.
我说我很想自己去沙漠里放松一晚
How I would love to go to the desert for a night alone.
我不在乎
I don't care.
如果你想自己去就自己去吧  我不在乎
If you want to go alone, go alone. I don't care.
瞧  你说了两次"我不在乎"
Oh, see, you said "I don't care" twice.
因为我就是那么不在乎
Because that's how much I don't care.
你怎么还不走
Why are you still here?
小卡  别受伤  我不是在逃离你
Cam, don't be hurt. I'm not running from you.
-拿着  -我才不要叠床单
- Here. - And I'm not folding that.
我只是想自己放松一晚  好吗
I just wanted a night alone, okay?
莉莉今晚要去朋友家过夜
Lily's going to that sleepover tonight.
我觉得今晚去正合适
It seemed like a good night to do it.
那就去啊
So, go!
我不喜欢你这像在暗示
You know, I don't love the implication
我缠人到不能自己过一晚的话
that I'm so needy I can't spend one night by myself.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
你也没没那么说
You didn't not say that.
你也没不缠人
And you're not not being needy.
为了向你展示我有多不缠人
Well, to show you how not needy I am,
我亲自帮你打包
I... will pack your bag for you.
你已经打包好了吗
It's already packed?
是的  这已经是我第三次
Oh, yeah, well, this is the third time
试着问你行不行了
I've tried asking you.
再见  我爱你  就这样
Bye. I love you. Okay.
你好  克莱尔
Oh, hello, Claire.
亲爱的
Hi, honey.
我刚从特别漂亮的...
I just got back from the most beaut-- Oh!
这反应就对了
Oh, indeed.
欢迎观看事先录好的视频诱惑
Welcome to your prerecorded seduction.
妈妈喜欢
Mama likes!
爸爸知道
Papa knows.
没错
That's right.
我如此了解我妻子  我能在她开口前
I know my wife so well, I was able to anticipate
就预测到她想问什么
her questions before she asked them.
这有点意思
Well, this is kind of fun.
全世界最性感吗
The sexiest?
我也不确定  毕竟人外有人天外有天
I don't know. The world's a pretty big place.
帮你自己倒杯葡萄酒  我的爱人
Help yourself to a glass of wine, my love.
现在时间还有点早
Oh, it's kind of early in the day,
但我们能有几次过二人时光的机会啊
but how often do we get the house completely to ourselves?
悠着点  小酒鬼
Easy, thirsty!
我还有好多计划等着你
I've got plans for you.
小提示  除了这块投影布
Hint -- This won't be the last time
今天你还会在床单布上看到我的肉体
you see me on a sheet today.
到你了
Now you.
看来我们得延后享用你做的精美午餐了
Well, I guess your beautiful lunch will have to wait.
家里来人了  不要  克莱尔
Someone's here! No, Claire!
什么
What?
没错  克莱尔  让我看看你的美脚
Yes, Claire. Show me those pretty feet.
这玩意怎么关
How do you turn this thing off?
投影布让我接着脱
The sheet said yes.
你们知道什么对学习毫无益处吗
You know what's not real conducive to studying?
上百个来自亚洲各国的书呆子的哭号
100 nerds crying in every different Asian language!
人人都知道期末考要到了好吗
You knew finals were coming, people.
都给我冷静点
Calm the hell down!
太好了  你们在家
Oh, good. You're here.
咱家有玉米吗
Do we have any corn?
这是什么情况
What is happening?
那些是鸡吗
Are those chickens?
史诗级高三恶作剧
Epic senior prank.
别搞得史诗过头  不然你明年怎么超越自己
Don't make it too epic. How will you top it next year?
把它们拎出去  拎出去
Get them out. Get them out.
-快快快  -我得上楼拿点东西
- Now, now, now. - I need to grab something upstairs.
我的天  搞什么  伙计们
Oh, God. Come on, guys.
又有人进门了  到底是怎么回事
The door! What is going on?
你们猜我遇见谁刚好开车经过附近
Guess who I found driving through the neighborhood
非坚持要带着新婚妻子和孩子们
who insisted on stopping over to say hi
来咱家打个招呼
with his new wife and her kids!
是我  迪兰
It was me! Dylan.
记得吗  我们以前认识的
You know, from before?
-记得  -记得
-Yeah. -Yeah.
邓先生邓太太  这是我妻子
Mr. And Mrs. D, this is my wife,
伊莱恩·寇查博士
Dr. Elaine Kolchuck.
博士
Doctor?
是啊  我不知道他为什么非要加上博士
Yeah, I don't know why he does that.
这两位是我的宝贝女儿
And these are my beauties,
贝蒂和珍尼丝
Betty and Janice.
这是我儿子道格拉斯
And this is my son Douglas.
你儿子
Your son.
一点都不奇怪
That's not weird.
总之  我只是想
Anyway, I just wanted to pick
来拿走我留在这的东西
something up that I left here.
看
Bam!
等一下
Oh, wait. Uh...
看  你们老爸拼的
Bam! Your dad did that.
黄色是最难拼的一面
Yellow's the hardest side.
那是什么声音  怎么了
What is that sound? What happened?
我把楼梯栏杆撞坏了  我会修好的
Brooke the banister. I'll fix it!
这是什么东西
What's this thing?
别碰  别碰
No! No!
-不  -现在...
- Oh, no! - And now...
不不不
No, no, no, no!
给你养养眼
A treat for you.
不  不
No! No!
全都给我回家去
Everybody go home!
不
No!
* 把脚放在茶几上看体育比赛 *
* Watching sports with my feet on the table *
* 这样最棒了 *
* This is the best *
* 自己待着最棒了 *
* Being alone is the best *
《救救我》
"Rescue Me."
什么
What?
上周吃晚餐时
That was the name of the TV show
我想不起来的电视剧名叫《救救我》
I couldn't remember at dinner last week.
来  我们一起看
Come on. Let's pop it in.
现在不是时候  小卡
No. It's a bad time, Cam.
原来我不是过敏
Turns out, it wasn't the allergies.
我现在病得难受
I feel terrible.
你不要靠得太近  我不想害你被传染
You shouldn't be close to me. I don't want to get you sick.
我不会被传染的
Oh, gosh. No danger of that.
我具有马的免疫系统
I have the immune system of a horse.
小时候  我有次需要输血
When I was a kid, I needed a transfusion,
结果给我输错了马血
and there was a mix-up with the vials.
我联系了漫威漫画公司很多次
I've contacted Marvel Comics repeatedly,
但他们好像并不感兴趣
but they don't seem interested.
来  我给你煮点鸡汤
Come on. I'll make you some chicken soup.
曼尼  你好吗
Manny! Hey, hey!
这位是谁呀
And who is this?
小卡  这是希拉  我的...
Cam, this is Sierra, my --
哎哟  你说我们现在算什么关系呢
Gosh, what would you call us at this point?
老师分配的学习搭档
Teacher-assigned study partners.
如你所见  我有很多功课要做  所以...
As you can see, I've got a lot of work to do, so...
是的  我们只剩半小时时间了
Yeah, we only have another half-hour.
我答应了我爸  我会去给车换机油
I promised my dad I'd get an oil change.
曼尼可以帮你换
Oh, well, Manny can do that.
真的吗
Really?
真的啊  把你的车停进车库
Yeah! Pull your car into the garage.
当心别撞到他的杠铃片或电动工具就行了
Just be careful not to hit his weight set or his power tools.
那真的太棒了
Wow. That would be awesome.
小卡  我知道你是想帮我  但别这么做
Cam, I know you're trying to help, but stop.
我对车子一窍不通
I'm clueless about cars,
而且我真的怕她会撞到我妈的杠铃片
and I really don't want her hitting Mom's weight set.
我会一步步教你的
I'm gonna talk you through it.
好了  美女  不管你在忙什么
Okay, missy, whatever you're working on over here,
都让我来帮你吧
let me take over.
不不不  你帮不了
No, no, no. You can't.
这是我外婆的独门退烧药
This is my abuela's special fever cure.
麻烦你把干蝎子递给我
Please hand me the dried scorpion.
你要吃这个吗
You're gonna eat this?
不是  别犯傻了
No, don't be stupid.
我是打算用块布包着它
I am gonna wrap it in a rag
然后盖在额头上  让它渗进去
and I am gonna let it soak into my head.
好的  要不这样吧
Okay. You know what?
你先到床上躺着  我待会给你送来
Let's get you to bed, and I will bring it to you.
我知道怎么按药方准备  快去
I can follow a recipe. Go on.
不不不  这样...
No, no, no. It's --
快去吧
Go on.
小心点
Be careful.
好了  鸡喙粉末
All right. Ground chicken beak.
蟋蟀泥
Mashed crickets.
恶心  还有香菜
Ew! Cilantro? Ugh.
我去给您拿门卡  洗手间在那边
I'll grab your room key. Restroom's over there.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
我一路开车来没停过  又喝了一大杯冰茶  所以...
I just drove the whole way. I had a huge iced tea, and --
我干嘛解释  你知道人类为什么要尿尿的
What am I doing? You know why people pee.
科林
Hey, Colin.
我刚才说不需要酒店地图  可能太草率了
Might have been hasty turning down that site map.
我已经误闯进同一个犹太成人礼两次了
I've walked into the same Bar Mitzvah twice now.
你在这里干嘛
Hey! Whatcha doing here?
我
Me?
你之前说小卡不会让你来的
You said Cam wouldn't let you come.
我还以为会很安全
I thought it was safe.
什么很安全  安全偷走我的特别日吗
Safe to what, steal my special day?
你形容得这么美妙
Well, you made it sound so good!
游泳池  牛排  不用跟人聊天
The pool, the steak, no one to talk to.
现在我们得跟人聊天了
Well, now we have someone to talk to.
"谢谢"你啊
Thanks a lot.
这地方很大
Look, the place is gigantic.
你干你的事  我忙我自己的
You do your thing, I'll do mine.
天啊
Oh, my God.
爸  你抄袭抄到连我在看的书都不放过
Dad, you even stole the book that I'm reading.
你来家里时
When you were over at the house,
-我偷瞄了封面  -当然了
- I peeked at the jacket. - ‭Of course.
我能不看拉里·金推荐说"好到爆"的书吗
I'm not gonna read something Larry King called "Crazy good"?
美国家喻户晓的脱口秀主持人
行吧  我们回文明社会再见  好吗
Fine. I'll see you back in civilization, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
你真的不需要酒店地图吗
Uh, you sure you don't need a site map.
不用了  没关系
Oh, no. I'm fine.
我已经来过无数次了  谢谢
I've been here a million times. Thank you so much.
犹太成年礼
你们想害我考试不及格吗
Are you trying to make me fail?!
亲爱的  我知道你压力很大
Sweetheart, I know that you're stressed,
而且我们感到很骄傲
and we are so proud
你紧张时不会再拔睫毛
that you stopped pulling out your eyelashes.
真心骄傲  但我们有点担心
So proud. We are a little concerned
你把笔塞进鼻子里这种新毛病
about this new, uh, pen-up-the-nose tic.
这  这才不是毛病
It's -- It's not a tic!
只是某些人偶尔会做的事  很正常
It's just something some people do occasionally.
-笔盖去哪儿了  -就在...
- Where is it -- - It's right --
就在  就在鼻孔里塞着呢
It's right -- You got it right there.
我靠
Ah! Damn it!
最好笑的是
I mean, the crazy thing is
我很开心迪兰跟那个有仨丑逼孩子的老女人在一起
I'm happy Dylan found that old lady with those hideous kids.
这有多搞笑啊
I mean, how funny is it
他居然先定下来了
that he is the one that settled down
活得那么幸福  而我却基本注定孤独终老
and is doing so great while I'm alone basically forever?
你能不能到别的地方当怨妇
Could you please go be tragic somewhere else?
迪兰  是你回来了吗
Dylan, are you back?
我在修楼梯栏杆
I'm fixing the banister!
这里简直就是噩梦
This is a nightmare!
你没比我们强好吗
You're not better than us.
我当然比你们强多了
I am so much better than you!
把笔塞进鼻孔的人不是我
I'm not the one with the pen up her nose.
至少我有男友
At least I have a boyfriend.
多恶毒的人才说得出这种话啊
Who says that?
天啊
Oh, God.
-天啊  -海莉为迪兰伤心哭闹
- Oh, God! ‭- Haley crying about Dylan,
艾丽克斯为学业崩溃
Alex freaking out about school,
这一切仿佛似曾相识
this is like a big deja vu.
不  似曾相识是指
No, deja vu is when you imagine
好像曾经经历过  其实没有
that you've seen something before.
我们这是"真经历"
This is just vu!
说句马后炮  我应该在把栏杆钉回去前
In hindsight, I should have pulled my head out
先把头缩回来
before I nailed the post back in.
兄弟
Buddy...
经一事长一智
Live and learn.
你要是真的长过智就好了
If only you ever did.
好了
Okay.
我这次好像真的玩太大了
I think I may have gone too deep this time.
要了个亲命啊  好多血啊
Sweet Caligula, that's a lot of blood.
迪兰为什么要换电话号码
Why would Dylan change his phone number?
你们知道他上次把号码背下来花了多长时间吗
Do you know how long it took him to memorize the last one?!
两边鼻孔都开始流血了吗
Both sides now?
别怪胶水的臭味
Don't hate this glue smell.
现在因为失血  开始头痛了
Now comes the blood-loss migraine.
这样吧  我去买点药
Oh, you know what? I-I can go get some medicine.
不不  还是我去吧
Oh, no. You know, I can do that.
事实上  我的车挡住了你的
Actually, my car's blocking your car.
那不是大问题  知道为什么吗
Yeah, that's not a big deal. You know why?
因为我可以开你的车  不开自己的  再见
Because I can take your car instead of mine! Bye!
不  不不  不可能
No. No, no, no! No way!
天啊
Oh, my God.
给我闭嘴
Knock it off!
少多管别人闲事
Mind your own business!
我也想
I would love to.
但现在我很好奇  你那些惊呼
But now I'm wondering if all that gasping
是跟我已经看过的内容有关  还是未看到的
is about something I've already read or something coming up!
我看到312页
I'm on page 312.
别告诉我啊
Don't tell me that!
这下我知道20页后会出现令我惊呼的情节了
Now I know there's a gasp coming in 20 pages.
当然了  你在跟踪我
Of course. You're following me.
抱歉  我还以为你是别人
Oh, I-I'm sorry. I thought you were someone else.
我刚刚到底目睹了什么可怕之事
What the hell did I just witness?
天啊
Oh, good Lord.
我勒个天啊
Oh! Good Lord!
再跟我介绍一下今日推荐的鲈鱼
Tell me about this sea bass special again.
以地中海风味腌制后用锡纸包着
Mediterranean prep, en papillote --
真的吗
Oh. Really?
是的
Yeah.
锡纸内放入番茄  红椒  刺山柑
Baked in paper with tomato, red pepper,
洋葱和橄榄一起烤
capers, onion, olives.
绝对是我最喜欢的鱼料理
Literally my favorite fish dish.
比起牛排  你会更推荐鲈鱼吗
Would you recommend that over the steak?
我在享受私人时间  你别打扰
Hey, I was kind of in the middle of my own thing here.
比起牛排  你会更推荐鲈鱼吗
Would you recommend it over the steak?
都很美味
They're both great.
好吧  牛排  照计划行事
Fine. Steak. Stick with the plan.
然后我要来一杯梅利维尔红酒
And I'll have a glass of the Merryvale Cab.
我也来一杯  谢谢
Yeah, me too. Thank you.
抱歉  梅利维尔红...  只以瓶贩卖
Sorry, the Merryvale Ca-- uh, doesn't come by the glass.
貌似两位好像互相认识
I-It seems like you two know each other.
你们可以点鱼跟牛排分着吃
You could split the fish and steak
再一起分享一瓶红酒啊
and share the bottle of wine.
谢了  不要
Not doing that.
我也没说过要啊
Never said we were.
其实这位是我爹
This is actually my dad.
我来这里是想要独处一阵  但他抄袭我
I came here for some alone time, but he copycatted me.
他明明说了不会来
He said he wasn't coming
因为他可怕的伴侣说不许他来
because his scary partner said he couldn't.
可怕的老公
Scary husband!
听起来还是别扭
Still hits my ear wrong.
你们都不打算...
Wow. So, you're not even gonna...
对不起
I-I'm sorry.
我只是...  我父亲在我十岁时去世了
Uh, just, my dad passed away when I was 10,
我愿付出一切跟他再共进晚餐
and I'd love to have dinner with him again.
奥斯丁  太可怜了
Oh, Austin. That's so sad.
烂故事
Terrible story.
害人得扪心自问
Makes you think.
言归正传  随便给我来杯别的红酒
Anyway, I'll have a glass of any of the reds.
我要白葡萄酒
White for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉啦  小兄弟
I'm sorry, buddy.
我不是故意这么用力拉你的腿的
I didn't mean to pull your leg so hard.
什么
What?!
迪伦一直是我的备胎
Dylan was my romantic safety net.
人没了备胎还怎么活啊
How is a person supposed to live without one?
艾丽克斯  我在问你呢
Alex, I'm asking!
从科学角度来说
It is scientifically impossible
我懒得鸟你破事的程度已到达极限
for me to care less about your -- Ow!
头朝下  亲爱的
Head down, honey.
-你说什么  -你们妈妈呢
- What?! - ‭Where is your mom?
她都不见了一个小时了
She's been gone for over an hour.
她就坐在车子里
She's just sitting in the car.
-什么  -什么
- What?! - ‭What?!
她就坐在...  算了
She's just sitting -- Never mind!
你好啊
Oh! Hi.
你好啊  你坐在这里多久了啊
Hi. How long you been sitting out here?
什么怪问题  我才刚开回来停下车
That's a weird question. I literally just drove in.
抱歉  我们通常都会在30分钟内送达的
Sorry. We usually try to get here in under 30 minutes.
谢谢  好的
Yeah, thank you. Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊  菲尔  我不能回去
Oh, God. Phil, I can't go back in there.
对不起  我试过了
I'm sorry. I tried.
我打开车门  但我的脚却抬不起来
I opened the door, but my legs wouldn't move.
亲爱的
Honey...
开车
Drive.
什么  那艾丽克斯的药怎么办
What? What about Alex's pills?
开车
Drive.
所以...我们就这么逃家了吗
So -- So we're running away from home.
这么做没关系吗
I mean, I-I-is that okay?
没关系  我们是跟三个成年人同住
Yes. We live with three adults.
我们就跟出租公寓楼的房东差不多
We're basically landlords in an apartment building.
我们就是《妙房东》
We're the Ropers!
以电视剧《三人行》中房东夫妇为主题的衍生剧
《三人行》的主角刚好也是两女一男
对的  没错  我们想开去哪就开去哪
Yes! Yes! We could just drive and drive.
没错  我们辛苦了多年
Exactly! We've earned the right to
空巢老人的生活是我们应得的
live the empty-nesters' life
哪怕现在巢里还孩满为患
even though we're still full-nesters.
天啊
Oh, my God!
你还记得那一瓶
Do you remember that bottle of wine
在海莉出生当晚我们特意留的那红酒吗
we put aside the night Haley was born?
记得  我们本来打算
Yes! We were gonna open it
在他们三个人搬走的那晚打开
the night all three of them moved out.
然后一起看我们因为他们
And watch one of the thousands of movies we missed
生病或肚子饿
'cause they were sick or hungry
或被玩具噎到而错过的无数电影
or choking on the head of a Power Ranger.
我是个还没看过《末路狂花》的女人
I am a woman who has never seen "Thelma and Louise."
那是我唯一错过的哈维·凯特尔电影
That's the only Harvey Keitel movie I've missed!
该美国知名男演员有在名电影《末路狂花》中出演
我们开去哪
Where are we going?
让上天为我们安排吧
Let's let the universe decide.
"家人是你每天都收到的上天礼物"
"Family is a gift you receive every day."
现在还有讽刺内容的签文了吗
So they're making sarcastic ones now?
松鼠
Squirrel!
我们好像毁了某人的毕业典礼
I think we just ruined someone's graduation.
我肯定是睡着了
Ay! I must have fallen asleep.
不会吧
I don't see how.
那药冒出来的气味可真是不同凡响啊
The fumes coming off of that potion are something else.
是啊  等用完了以后  别扔掉
Yes. When we're done with this, don't throw it out
只需一茶匙  我能清理干净整个泳池
because with a teaspoon, I can clean the swimming pool.
好了  曼尼需要我去车库找他
Okay, Manny needs to see me in the garage.
我很快回来
I will be right back.
但一定要快啊
Yeah, but come right back
这东西不能用超过五分钟
because this cannot stay longer than five minutes.
就好奇一问  如果这东西
Oh, and just for fun, what would happen
用了比如说17分钟会怎么样啊
if it stayed on for, say, I don't know, 17?
人家说...
Well, they say that --
惨了
Ay, no!
不要啊
No!
你用乔的宝贝披风来包这臭东西吗
You used Joe's cape for this smelly thing?
-你知道这东西对他多重要吗  -不知道
- You know how important this is for him? ‭- No.
心中重要度是从我  斗篷  巧克力碎饼干
It goes me, the cape, chocolate chip cookies,
再到杰
and then Jay!
那我们能不能就说是杰搞的
Well, can't we just say Jay ruined it,
反正他已经在名单底层了
since he's already so far down the list?
你们有人看到我的斗篷吗
Has anyone seen my cape?
没有  它长什么样
Uh, no. What's it look like?
斗篷样啊
Like a cape!
对不起  没了它我压力好大
Sorry. It's just so stressful.
这样吧  我先去帮曼尼
You know what? I have to go to Manny.
然后洗乔的斗篷  再回来找你
Then I'll clean Joe's cape. Then I'll be back.
没事  去吧
It's okay. Go.
我们会在度假胜地坎昆这里等你
We will all be waiting for you here in Cancun.
有哪里出了问题  到处都是油
Something's wrong. There's oil everywhere!
估计只需要弄紧放油塞就行了
Well, you probably just need to tighten the drain plug.
你戳爆了她轮胎吗
You popped her tire?!
没事  没关系的
It's okay. It's all right.
杰都把补胎工具收哪了
Where does Jay keep his patch kit?
我花了20分钟才找到这里灯的开关
It took 20 minutes to find the light switch.
我能知道补胎工具在哪吗
I'm gonna know where a patch kit is?
别恐慌  我之前有在这里看到
Don't panic. I saw one here earlier.
找到啦
Here it is.
-别啊  别  -干嘛
- Oh, no! No! - ‭What?
那是乔的斗篷
That's Joe's cape!
不是吧
Oh, no!
这是乔最爱的东西了
Joe loves this cape more than anything.
心中重要度顺序是我  斗篷  巧克力碎饼干
It goes me, the cape, chocolate chip cookies --
要好了吗  曼尼
Almost done, Manny?
你来啦
Oh, hey.
其实早能好了  都是被我拖延进度
Yeah, well, he would be if I wasn't out here
回答了我一堆问题  比如说...
asking him so many questions about, you know,
怎么补车胎之类的  但就像他说的
how to -- how to patch a tire, but like he said,
补车胎的方法全都清楚写在
the directions are written clearly down
补胎工具包里了
inside the patch kit.
就算真的很棘手
And then if you get in a real jam,
网上也有无数教学影片啊
there's tons of videos online, anyway.
我们给他一点工作空间吧
Shouldn't we give him some space?
比如我们可以去喝杯茶
Maybe get some -- some tea?
春季舞会有舞伴了吗
So, do you have a date for spring formal?
我估计都不会去吧  我没合适的服装
I probably won't even go. I have nothing to wear.
天啊  天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
也没这么严重啦
It's not that big of a deal.
世上还有人没饭吃呢
I mean, people are starving.
这不是什么迹象[指示牌]吧
This isn't a sign, is it?
绝对不是结实的指示牌  毕竟是五年级生搭的
Well, it's not a sturdy one, but they're only fifth-graders.
不是啦  我是说不该逃离家里的迹象
No! No, that we shouldn't have run away!
才不是  我们把这个绑好就能继续上路
No. We're just gonna tie this off, hit the open road,
一直开  开到冲马桶时
and keep driving until the toilets flush
漩涡旋转方向相反之地[南半球]
in the other direction.
天啊  要飘走了
Oh, God! Oh, no! It's floating away!
没事
Oh! Oh, okay!
卡在树上了  我们能拉回来
It's caught in the tree, we can reach it.
-上我肩膀  -什么
- Get on my shoulders! - What?
是啊  对的
Right! Oh, yeah, right. Oh!
对哦  我都忘了这招
Okay, I forgot about that.
等等  往前进
Oh, wait. Go forward!
太高了
It's too high!
抓那个线就行了  你是在抓那个线吗
Just reach for the string! Are you reaching for the string?
不是  我在假装看演唱会
No, I'm pretending I'm at a Def Leppard concert!
就在那里  你抓啊
It's right there! Just grab it!
我够不到  菲尔
I can't reach it, Phil!
我够不到"人生下一章"
I can't reach "The Next Chapter!"
我的天啊  放我下来  放我下来吧
Oh, my God. Let me down. Let me down.
-怎么了  -放我下来
- What? - Let me down.
怎么啦
What?
你没看出上天给我们的旨意吗
Don't you see what the universe is trying to tell us?
我们永远也到不了"人生下一章"
We are never gonna reach the next chapter.
卢克不会去上大学
Luke's not going to college.
海莉会在我们地下室住到老
Haley's gonna grow old in the basement.
艾丽克斯只会一直回来嘲讽我们
Alex is just gonna keep coming back to taunt us
然后用完我们的纸巾
and use up our tissues!
我觉得老天爷没对我们那么"关照"吧
I don't think the universe cares that much about us.
菲尔  我们想逃跑
Phil, we tried to run away,
但我从这里都还看得到我们家烟囱
and I can still see our chimney from here.
放弃吧
It's over.
好的  够了
Oh, yeah. This is it.
"欢迎来到
"Welcome...
我们的人生"
to our life!"
宝贝  我跟你一样不开心
Sweetheart, I-I am as upset as you are,
但事情本来就从未按我们计划的来过啊
but since when did anything work out the way we planned?
我们没计划过生海莉
We didn't plan on having Haley.
也没计划再生艾丽克斯
We didn't plan on having Alex.
我们的确是计划过生卢克
We did plan on having Luke,
但没计划过生出"卢克"这样的
but we didn't plan on having Luke.
我在闹脾气  但我也爱我们的孩子  真的
I'm having a tantrum. And I love our kids, I do.
大多数时候  我真的爱
Most of the time, I do.
只是在我心里
It's just I had this --
我有过对我们这阶段人生的憧憬
this picture of how our life would look right now.
不是现在这样子
This is not that.
完全不是
No.
是啊
Yeah.
我懂
I get it. ‭
或许...
Maybe...
或许我们不用放弃那憧憬
Maybe we don't have throw away the picture.
重新调整一下就行了
Just refocus it a little.
《末路狂花》
轮爪螺母  撬胎棒
Lug nut. Tire iron.
格尔锤  鸽子门
Flugel hammer. Pigeon door.
这些词对我而言都是火星话
These are all nonsense words to me.
我都不知道我在这里干什么
I don't know what I'm doing here.
是啊  我也不知道我在这里干嘛啊
Yeah, well, I don't know what I'm doing here, either.
难道我就真的连独处一晚都不行
Am I so incapable of spending a night alone
还得跑来你家制造这么多麻烦吗
that I had to come over here and create all this drama?
难怪米奇尔想逃离我
No wonder Mitchell wanted to get away from me.
你们好了吗
Hello?
谢谢你啊  曼尼
Oh! Hey, well, thank you, Manny,
给我一个把最后的螺母拧紧的机会
for letting me tighten that last wheel screw.
或许下周你可以教我怎么街头式出拳
Maybe next week you could teach me how to street punch?
可以啊  没问题
Yeah. Sure!
小卡在楼上帮我找到的
Cam found it upstairs for me.
这件是你妈妈的裙子  是不是很怪啊
It's one of your mom's dresses. Isn't that crazy?
跟心理医生聊两句就没事了
I can see running it by a therapist.
看起来车好像弄好了
So, car looks done.
你有兴趣去...  比如说
Do you maybe want to, I don't know,
一起吃个东西之类的吗
go get something to eat?
没问题啊  但我身上有点脏
Uh, sure! But I'm a little dirty.
那又如何  挺可爱的啊
So? It's cute.
聊聊吗
A word?
你看
See?
就跟新...
Good as --
天啊
No! Oh.
看起来像被怪兽啃过
It looks like a monster ate it!
没错
Exactly.
你看  这代表你很有故事
See? It tells a story.
这是你跟恶龙大战时被它吐火烧的
This burn is from when you fought a dragon!
而这些油污呢
A-And these oil stains?
是在你拯救要掉下桥的
Well, they're from when you saved that 18-wheeler
加长大卡车时沾到的
from going off a bridge.
这是个超级英雄的斗篷
This is the cape of a superhero
他永远在人们需要时出现
who's always there for people in need.
飞走吧
Fly away!
你说得真好  小卡
That was so nice, Cam.
谢谢  你看起来好多了
Thanks. You look better.
你的烧也退了
And your fever's gone.
我不知道你在我外婆的药里加了什么
I don't know what you put in my abuela's potion,
但这次烧退得比以前任何一次都快
but it took care of the fever faster than ever.
你看  甚至还让我的牙变白了
Look! It even made my teeth whiter, huh?
你看看
Oh! Wow. Look at that.
我本来还在怨自己独处不了
Here I was beating myself up because I couldn't be alone,
但或许有人会觉得这个家里的所有人
and one could argue that everybody in this house
因为我的毛病而得到了好处
is a little better off because of it.
我损失了一条裙子  家里一股烧焦味
Well, I lost a dress and the house smells like smoke,
如果是我  我也不会过分自豪
so I wouldn't be high-fiving myself that much.
有事吗  先生
Ah, yes, sir?
对吧
Right?
没人可以把我的心悬在半空500页
Nobody keeps me on edge for 500 pages
然后故事说结束就结束
then decides they're just done writing.
你要么好好收尾  要么就根本别开始写
Either end the damn story or don't even write it!
对啊  就是嘛
Yes, exactly.
天啊  我还一度以为我哪里漏读[错过]了
God, for a minute, I thought I missed something.
是啊
You did.
你错过了你独处的夜晚读到一本好书的机会
The chance to read a great book on your one night alone.
至少牛排还蛮好吃的  对吧
Well, at least the steak was good, right?
肉的部位好  烹调得更好
Nice cut. Perfectly cooked.
酒也好喝
Terrific wine.
怎么  怎么  哪里好笑了
What? What's -- What's funny?
你啊
You.
牛排  书  这整段旅程
The steak, the book, hell, this whole trip.
你在变成我
You're turning into me!
没  才没有
No. No. Unh-unh.
才不是呢  爸  不不不
No, no, no. Dad. No, no.
是你在变成我
Hey. You're turning into me.
怎么说
How?
你居然能坚持把那本书看完
The fact that you stayed with that book at all,
这基本上就是两个男人的爱情故事
which is basically a love story between two men.
是兄弟情好吗
It's a buddy thing!
你少来了
Oh, please!
兄弟才不会找那么多机会
Buddies don't find that many opportunities
一起裸泳呢
to skinny-dip together.
每次只要他们一到水边
Every time they saw a body of water,
他们就脱裤子  跳进水里
it was off with the pants, splash!
拜托  别再把那书说得更恶心了
Come on. You're just making it worse.
天啊  你的手
Oh, my God! Your hands!
原来你预约水疗是为了这个
That's what your spa appointment was.
你去做了美甲
You got a manicure.
我去做是因为歌洛莉亚说我的手太粗糙
It's because Gloria said that my hands were too rough.
是她的主意
It was her idea.
体贴  我的风格
Considerate -- That's me.
逃离家人  我的风格
Running from your family -- That's me.
是啦  是啦
Yeah, yeah.
或许有可能是
Ah, I guess it's possible
我们两个都往彼此的中间移动了一点
that we both moved to the center a little.
是啦  挺有道理的
Yeah, well, it makes sense.
这样也让我们相处之间容易许多
It definitely makes things easier between us.
也少了点距离感
A little less distance.
是啊
Yeah.
是啦
我有一个...
Uh, hey, um... here's a --
有个疯狂的想法
It's a crazy thought.
有一件  有一件我们过去的自己
There's -- There's something old us could never do
不飙泪不骂人就做不到
without tears and screaming
但我觉得新的彼此可以做到的事
that I think new us might be able to handle.
这可以帮我在家里提升地位  如果你愿意帮的话
It might help me out at home, you know, if -- if you're game.
以手肘带动
Lead with your elbow.
转移你的重心
Shift your weight.
把球投出
Follow through.
不差
That's not bad.
但也不好  不过好歹我没在哭
No, it wasn't good, but I'm not crying
你也还没开始叫我"小姐"  继续吧
and you haven't called me "Missy", so let's keep going.
他们没得选了
They had no choice.
钩子上放了饵食就会亮红灯
The light turns red when you put something on it,
当饵食没了就会亮绿灯
green when the hook is free.
-我把它成为智能神钩  -太神了
- I call it a Smart Hook. - So smart.
这主意是我在室内停车场时受到启发
I got the idea... when I was in a parking garage.
-你知道他们的指示灯...  -天啊  爸  别回头看
- You know those little lights... - Oh, God, Dad. No, don't look.
-别看  -他们在这里干嘛
- Don't look. - What are they doing here?
他们不会想跟我们一起共进早午餐吧
They're not gonna want to have brunch with us, are they?
不可以  这是我们的日子
They can't! This is our day!
你觉得他们有看到我们吗
You think they see us?
继续走就对了
Just keep walking.
不要有突然的大动作
No sudden movements.
地图上写着这里还有另一家咖啡厅
The site maps say there's another cafe...
-我的书  -别捡了
- My book. - Leave it!